Xenia Shtokolova

Minneapolis, MN ↑
*Searching for a position in the Chicago area
612-757-1173 ►

xeniashtokolova@gmail.com linkedin.com/xenia-shtokolova in https://xeniashtokolova.github.io #

Enthusiastic Business Data Analyst with 3+ years of experience interpreting and analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Proven capability to find patterns and derive business outcomes from large-scale datasets with proficiency in using SQL, SSRS, Power BI, Tableau and Excel Ad-hoc reporting.

Skills

- SQL, Tableau, PowerBI, SSRS, SSIS, AWS, ServiceNow, OneDrive/SharePoint, Excel, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Visio, yEd, RX claims, AS 400, Jira, Confluence
- Ability to translate business needs into requirements and distill insights from data
- Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders in order to deliver on business objectives

Experience

APRIL, 2021 - PRESENT

Business Data Analyst / Bailiwick, Chaska MN

- Create and oversee plans to accurately manage inventory levels and ensure proper forecasting by utilizing historical data, past sales trends, and market information
- Assist in structuring of presentations for budget meetings and board reviews
- Provide analytic supports for key business activities (strategic initiatives, campaigns design, customer segmentation strategy etc.)
- Act as a liaison between technical staff and business owners.
- Develop charts, diagrams, training material, structured communications, and other relevant documentation to accurately capture and communicate a variety of complex requirements, issues, options, and solutions to a broad audience.

AUGUST,2020 – APRIL,2021

Quality Assurance Analyst III / Prime Therapeutics, Eagan MN

- Provided Benefit Edit Tool submission support to clients. Respond and resolve client submission questions and/or issues in a timely manner
- Partnered with QA Analysts Team to ensure that applications and solutions meet business and quality requirements
- Wrote reports summarizing findings for leadership, prepared slides for presentations by leadership
- Designed and built visually rich applications and dashboards to measure, track, and display key business metric using Power BI to help improve business processes

JANUARY,2018 – AUGUST,2020

Project Coordinator - Analyst / Millz House, Apple Valley MN

- Analyzed and evaluated the business processes a company has and identified areas of improvement
- Perform ad-hoc analysis to find solutions to business inquiries
- Prepared ad-hoc business reports and, conducted comprehensive analysis with written summaries providing recommendations to senior executives (Tableau, Excel)
- Analyzed and identified opportunities for improvement and standardization

JULY ,2017 - JANUARY,2018

Management Trainee / University of Minnesota MAST International program, St Paul, MN

MAST is an international exchange program dedicated to promoting mutual understanding and building long-term international relationships by organizing paid management training in the USA. One of the 20 student selected by UN in Ukraine.

- Maintained quality reports and customer service requests and complaints
- Managed tasks, deliverables, and reported related to project status and created documentation
- Analyzed large amounts of information, and managed related data with Microsoft Access

Education

FEBRUARY,2022

Business Analyst Certificate / University of Minnesota, Carlson School of ManagementNOVEMBER.2018

Project Management Certificate / University of Minnesota, Carlson School of Management

FEBRUARY,2015

MBA / Kharkiv Petro Vasylenko National Technical University

* Master's degree – completed 6 years program which is equivalent to U.S. Master's Degree

Leadership

JULY,2019 - PRESENT

Volunteer at Business Intelligence Department / Minnesota Historical Society, Saint Paul, MN

- Helping to create business flow diagrams for historic site daily retail reconciliation, identifying differences in processes across sites
- Helping to create institution-wide diagrams of technology system programs using Power BI
- Helping to build short term and long-term roadmaps

FEBRUARY, 2019 - PRESENT

Public Relations Officer/ Big Apple Toastmaster, Apple Valley, MN

- Assisting in the organizing of promotional events and campaigns
- Developing and implementing marketing projects
- Regularly giving speeches, gaining feedback, leading teams, and guiding others to achieve their goals